Guide to the Cannon Mills Records, 1836-1983 RL.00187
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Harold P. Hornaday Series, 1971-1982
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Expense Reports, 1971-1980, 2 folders (Box 130)
    - Speeches, 1973-1980, 3 folders (Box 131)
- Joseph C. Ridenhour Series, 1944-1956
  Files of this long-time official concerning advertising, ceiling prices, and the Laboratory Department. Includes some correspondence. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Advertising: (Box 131)
      - 1954 (Box 131)
      - Invoices Paid: 1953–1954 (Box 131)
    - Ceiling Prices:
      - 1944, 1949 (Box 131)
      - 1950 (Box 131)
      - 1951 (Box 131)
    - Correspondence:
      - 1953 (Box 131)
      - 1956 (Box 131)
    - Laboratory Department, 1954, Jan.-April, 2 folders (Box 131)
    - Laboratory Department, 1954, May-Dec., 4 folders (Box 132)
- Hearne Swink Series, 1955
  Correspondence and statistical compilations relating to labor, production, and marketing. Swink was vice president and secretary of the company.
  - Boxed File
    - Correspondence and Statistical Reports: (Box 132)
      - 1955, Jan.-Dec. (Box 132)
- Cotton Department Series, 1916-1970, bulk 1916-1917 and 1938-1970
  Correspondence principally among Charles A. Cannon, other officials of the company, and the Cotton Department concerning government regulation and the supply, marketing, acquisition, and utilization of cotton. Also cotton invoices for Franklin Cotton Mills, bills and lading, and account books. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Bills of Lading, 1938, Jan.-Feb. (Box 132)
    - Bills of Lading, 1938, March (Box 133)
    - Correspondence:
      - 1918, 1929-1930 (Box 133)
      - 1938, Aug.-Dec. (Box 133)
      - 1939-1963, 11 folders (Box 133)
    - Correspondence: (Box 134)
      - 1964-1970, 6 folders (Box 134)
    - Cotton Invoices for Franklin Cotton Mills:
      - 1916, July-Sept.-1917, Sept., 4 folders (Box 134)
    - Cotton Invoices for Franklin Cotton Mills: (Box 135)
      - 1917, Oct.-1918 and undated, 3 folders (Box 135)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Ledger, 1916-1924 (Volume 3)
    - Ledger, 1923-1924 (Volume 4)
    - Cashbook, 1928, Jan.-1932, Dec. (Volume 5)
- Cannon Manufacturing Company and Cannon Mills Series, 1888-1976
  Files and account books of the mother company and of the consolidated corporation beginning in 1928 including the factories at both Concord and Kannapolis (operating 30,000 and 125,000 spindles, respectively, in 1916). Includes minute books; stock records; files recording how the company implemented the state's early child labor laws (both boys and girls); superintendent's records; time books mostly from the Weave Room, Plant No. 1, arranged by the names of overseers and other supervisory personnel; financial statements and inventories; registers of employee injuries; geographical distribution of orders and billings; ledgers; journals; trial balances; cashbooks; bank ledgers; and miscellaneous files and account book for purchases, production, sales, construction, employees, and equipment. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Agreement of 1917 with Cabarrus Cotton Mills, Wiscassett Mills, J. W. Cannon, etc., Cancelled, 1920 (Box 135)
    - Blair, David Hunt, 1923 (Box 135)
    - Cannon and Fetzer Co. (Manufacturers' Agents and Jobbers of Shoes, Clothing, and Hats, Concord, N.C.):
      - 1902-1903, Feb. (Box 135)
      - 1903, March-1904 (Box 135)
    - Census of Manufacturers, 1919, 1921 (Box 135)
    - Checkbook Stubs for National Park Bank of New York, 1923-1928 (Box 135)
    - Chemistry Laboratory Blueprints, 1950-1951, Bemis Lester, Architect, Kannapolis, N.C. (Oversize-folder OC:IV.8)
    - Child Labor: (Box 135)
      - 1917-1932 and undated, 2 folders (Box 135)
    - Child Labor: (Box 136)
      - Age and Grade Certification, 1919-1928 and undated (Box 136)
      - Certificates, 1917-1936, 4 folders (Box 136)
    - Contracts, 1901-1906 and undated (Box 137)
    - Correspondence:
      - 1907, 1909, 1917, 1921-1926 and undated, 4 folders (Box 137)
    - Cotton Purchases Invoices, 1906-1907 (Box 137)
    - Cotton Receipts Book, 1931-1932 (Box 137)
    - Cotton Sheetings Purchase, 1906, April 6 (Box 137)
    - Cotton Storage Receipts and Negotiable Certificates of Cotton on Memoranda:
      - 1915-1916, 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Cotton Summaries, 1921-1922 (Box 137)
    - Crompton and Knowles Loom Works, Worcester, Mass:
      - Specifications for Looms and Parts, 1922- 1925 (4 vols.) (Box 137)
    - Crompton and Knowles Loom Works, Worcester, Mass: (Box 138)
      - Specifications for Looms and Parts, 1926 and undated (8 vols.) (Box 138)
    - Distribution of Expenses, 1921 (Box 138)
    - Employee Accident Expense, 1931-1934 (Box 138)
    - Employee Charges, Authorizations, etc., 1902-1904 and undated (Box 138)
    - Factory Insurance Association: 1909, Feb.-1910, 2 folders (Box 138)
    - Granger Foundry and Machine Co., 1901-1902 (Box 138)
    - Invoices:
      - 1921-1922 (Box 138)
      - Barringer Manufacturing Co., 1921-1922 (Box 138)
      - Franklin Cotton Mills, 1921-1922 (Box 138)
      - York, S.C., Plant, 1922 (Box 138)
    - Draper Corporation, Hopedale, Mass.: (Box 139)
      - Specifications for Looms and Parts, 1915- 1939 (19 vols.) (Box 139)
    - Invoice Letterpress Book, 1907, March-1908, Aug. (Box 140)
    - Invoice Letterpress Book, 1909, Oct.-1912, Jan. (Box 141)
    - Memorandum of Shipments, 1902-1903 (Box 142)
    - Mill No. 6 Construction, T. C. Thompson and Bros., 1920-1921, 6 folders (Box 142)
    - Miscellaneous Financial Papers, 1920-1922 (Box 142)
    - Letter, 1928 Concerning Minute Book, 1887- (Box 143)
    - Cannon Manufacturing Company, Minute Book, 1908- 1918 (Box 143)
    - Cannon Manufacturing Company, Minute Book, 1919- 1928 (Box 143)
    - Cannon Mills Company, Minute Book, 1928-1949 (Box 144)
    - Cannon Mills Company, Minute Book, 1950-1971 (Box 144)
    - Cannon Mills Company, Minute Book, 1972-1976, June (Box 145)
    - Cannon Mills Company, Minute Book, 1976, July-Sept. (Box 145)
    - Officers and Directors, List of: (Box 146)
      - 1915-1921 (Box 146)
    - Payroll, 1927, June 4 (Box 146)
    - Payroll and Other Expense Vouchers:
      - 1903-1904, 2 folders (Box 146)
    - Personnel:
      - Mill Workers Over 16 and Under 16 Years of Age, 1920 (Box 146)
    - Sales Invoices:
      - 1926-1929: A-C (Box 146)
      - 1923-1930: D-H (Box 146)
      - 1923-1930: K-P (Box 146)
      - 1926-1930: R-W (Box 146)
    - Southern Railway Company:
      - 1903-1913 and n.d, 6 folders (Box 146)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-235, 1888-1899 (Box 147)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 236-473, 1899-1908 (Box 147)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 474-717, 1908-1911 (Box 148)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 718-959, 1911-1916 (Box 148)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 960-998, 1916-1917 (Box 148)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 999-1241, 1917-1918 (Box 149)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1242-1461, 1918-1922 (Box 149)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-250, 1922 (Box 150)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 251-500, 1922 (Box 150)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 501-750, 1922 (Box 151)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 751-1000, 1922-1924 (Box 151)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1001-1250, 1924-1926 (Box 152)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1251-1394, 1926-1928 (Box 152)
    - Stock Ledger, 1915-1920: (Box 153)
      - Index (Box 153)
    - Stock Subscriptions to New Issue, 1918, 2 folders (Box 153)
    - Stock Transfers, 1888-1915 (Box 153)
    - Stockholder Lists, 1915, 1918, 1919 or 1920, undated (Box 153)
    - Stockholder Proxies:
      - 1922, Jan. (Box 153)
      - 1924, Jan. (Box 153)
      - 1928, Jan. 26 (Box 153)
    - Stockholders' Report, 1927 (Box 153)
    - Listing of Stockholders Who Received $500 or More in Dividends during 1932 (Oversize-box OV3)
    - Stonewall Cotton Mills, Stonewall, Mississippi: (Box 154)
      - 1912-1914, 2 folders (Box 154)
    - Superintendent's Letterpress Book, 1900, March-1901, June (Also includes accident reports, 1903, and earlier) (Box 154)
    - Superintendent's Daily Reports, 1901, March-Nov. (Includes letter, 1902, inventory, 1901, Aug. 1 and occasional accident reports) (Box 154)
    - Superintendent's Reports:
      - 1911-1919, 5 folders (Box 154)
      - Bleachery, 1915 (Box 154)
      - Bleachery, 1916 (Box 154)
    - Taxes:
      - State and Local, 1920-1921 (Box 154)
    - Telephone Numbers, ca. 1921 (Box 154)
    - Trial Balance, 1921, Dec. 31 (Box 154)
    - Time Books: (Box 155)
      - Mill No. 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 155)
      - Carl W. Barnard, 1934, Dec. 29-1939, Jan. 19, 2 vols. (Box 155)
      - Carl W. Barnard and H. C. Trull, 1936, March 7- June 27 (Box 155)
      - J. L. Beaver, 1915, Sept. 18-1920, Feb. 28, 3 vols. (Box 155)
      - J. E. Benson, 1925, Aug. 8-1934, Feb. 10, 9 vols. (Box 155)
      - H. C. Clawson, 1923, May 5-1927, Jan. 8, 7 vols. (Box 155)
    - Time Books: (Box 156)
      - Mill No. 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 156)
      - R. L. Cloninger, 1925, Dec. 26-1935, April 6, 10 vols. (Box 156)
      - R. L. Cloninger and G. M. Misenheimer, 1935, July 13-Sept. 21 (Box 156)
      - R. L. Hicks and M. H. Sides, 1919, Dec. 20-1920, Aug. 14 (Box 156)
      - R. L. Hicks, 1920, Aug. 28-1922, May 6, 3 vols. (Box 156)
      - J. W. Lentz, 1931, Aug. 29-1939, Feb. 2, 4 vols. (Box 156)
      - J. W. Lentz and F. G. Sloop, 1935, April 20-July 13 (Box 156)
    - Time Books: Mill No 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 157)
      - J. W. Lentz and F. G. Sloop, 1935, July 27-1938, Sept. 17, 8 vols. (Box 157)
      - J. W. Lentz and P. D. Wiseman, 1929, Feb. 16- Nov. 23 (Box 157)
    - Time Books: Mill No 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 158)
      - H. L. Lifford, 1923, June 2-1938, May 28, 9 vols. (Box 158)
      - W. L. Link, 1926, Dec. 25-1927, April 30 (Box 158)
      - Sank McCoy, 1922, May 20-1925, July 25, 7 vols. (Box 158)
      - L. W. Maulden, 1938, Oct. 1-1939, Jan. 5 (Box 158)
      - E. R. Morris and J. M. Howard, 1936, July 11-Oct. 17 (Box 158)
      - G. G. Odell, 1938, Nov. 26-1939, Jan. 19 (Box 158)
    - Time Books: Mill No. 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 159)
      - W. L. Paul, 1915. Nov. 13-1919, Nov. 22, 4 vols. (Box 159)
      - J. F. Perry, 1927, Feb. 19-1928, Feb. 18, 2 vols. (Box 159)
      - F. G. Sloop, 1933, July 1-1939, Jan. 19, 4 vols. (Box 159)
      - E. M. Spry, 1936, Sept. 19-1938, Sept. 17, 2 vols. (Box 159)
      - J. A. Talbert, 1918, Dec. 21-1921, Oct. 22, 6 vols. (Box 159)
    - Time Books: Mill No. 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 160)
      - J. A. Talbert, 1921, Nov. 5-1926, Sept. 4, 6 vols. (Box 160)
      - H. C. Trull, 1928, July 21-1937, Nov. 13, 7 vols. (Box 160)
      - H. C. Trull, Name Book, undated (Employees' names, addresses, places of origin, ages, political affiliation, etc.) (Box 160)
    - Time Books: Mill No. 1, Weave Room (Dates are at ends of pay periods): (Box 161)
      - F. C. Wagoner, 1926, March 20-Aug. 8 (Box 161)
      - Leck Willett, 1920, March 13-1923, May 19, 6 vols. (Box 161)
    - Time Book and Style Book for Looms, ca. 1915-1916 (Box 161)
    - Employee Name Book, 1927-1929 (Names, ages, addresses, places of origin, etc.) (Box 161)
    - Time Books:
      - Mill No. 2, Cloth Room, N.S. Anderson, 1928, April 14-1929, July 20 (Box 161)
      - Mill No. 6, Cloth Room, N.S. Anderson, 1928, April 14, 1930, March 1 (Box 161)
      - Mill No. 1, Slasher, W.G. Pennell and F. L. Rumple, 1937, Oct. 29-1939, Jan. 19 (Box 161)
      - Slasher Department Time Sheet, 1936, Dec. 26 (Box 161)
      - Mill No. 7, Weave Room, 1927, Feb. 5-March 5 (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous Sheets and Covers, 1920s-1930s (Box 161)
    - Time Books: Packing Room:
      - 1920-Jan., 1921, 5 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1922, 5 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1923, 9 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1924-Jan., 1925, 10 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1925, 9 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1926-Jan., 1927, 13 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1927, 10 vols. (Box 162)
      - 1928, 4 vols. (Box 162)
    - Time Sheets, Mills 1 and 3, 1913, Nov. 29 (Oversize-folder OC:IV:8)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Ledger No. 4, 1903-1904 (Volume 6)
    - Private Journal, 1913, April-1920, Aug. (Volume 7)
    - General Ledger, 1909-1920 (Oversize-folder OC:IV:8)
    - Subsidiary Ledger, 1916-1923 (Volume 8)
    - Journal No. 7, 1903, Aug.-1908, April (Volume 9)
    - Journal No. 8, 1908, April-1910, Dec. (Volume 10)
    - Journal No. 9, 1911, Jan.-1914, Feb. (Volume 11)
    - Journal No. 1, 1935, July-1935, Dec. (Volume 12)
    - Journal No. 2, 1936, Jan.-1946, Dec. (Volume 13)
    - Trial Balance Book for Private Ledger, 1916, Jan.-1919, July (Volume 14)
    - Trial Balance Book for Private Ledger, 1919, Aug.-1922, Sept. (Volume 15)
    - Financial Statements and Inventories, 1888-1911 (Volume 16)
    - Cashbook No. 1, 1903, May-1905 Feb. (Volume 17)
    - Cashbook No. 2, 1905, March-1906, Oct. (Volume 18)
    - Cashbook No. 3, 1906, Nov.-1908, April (Volume 19)
    - Cashbook No. 4, 1908, April-1909, July (Volume 20)
    - Cashbook No. 5, 1909, July-1910, Dec. (Volume 21)
    - Petty Cash Book, 1919, May-1925, April (Volume 22)
    - Petty Cash Book, 1925, May-1936, Dec. (Volume 23)
    - Cash Receipts Book (Including Payroll Returns), 1914, March-Dec. (Volume 24)
    - Cash Receipts Book (Including Payroll Returns), 1914, Nov.-1926, Dec. (Volume 25)
    - Bank Ledger B, 1899, June-1903, Jan. (Volume 26)
    - Bank Ledger C, 1903, Feb.-1909, Jan. (Volume 27)
    - Bank Ledger No. 5, 1931, May-1935, Dec. (Volume 28)
    - Bank Ledger No. 6, 1936, Jan.-1941, June (Volume 29)
    - Bank Ledger No. 7, 1941, July-1946, Sept. (Volume 30)
    - Accounts Receivable Register, 1903, July-Oct. (Volume 31)
    - Statements of Overdue Bills and Balances as of July 7, 1928, for the Accounts Receivable Ledger as Sent in from the Various Plants at the Time of the Consolidation (Volume 32)
    - Suspense or Doubtful Account Ledger, 1911-1929, for Cannon Manufacturing Co., Cannon Mills, Cannon and Co., Amazon Cotton Mills, Cabarrus Cotton Mills, Efird Manufacturing Co., Gibson Manufacturing Co., Patterson Manufacturing Co., Tuscarora Cotton Mill, and Wiscassett Mills (Volume 33)
    - Purchases Journal, 1906, Aug.-1907, Aug. (Volume 34)
    - Purchases Journal No. 2, 1919, June-1922, Oct. (Volume 35)
    - Cotton Purchases Record, 1910, Dec.-1915, Dec. (Volume 36)
    - Cotton Purchases Record, 1915, Dec.1920, Nov. (Volume 37)
    - Cotton Purchases Ledger, 1923-1929 (Including Personal Injury Voucher Record, 1928-1929) (Volume 38)
    - Cotton Purchases Ledger, 1926-1931 (Volume 39)
    - Payroll Distributions, 1911-1921 (Volume 40)
    - Payroll Returned, 1906, Sept.-1912, April (Volume 41)
    - Payroll Returned, 1912, April-1913, Nov. (Volume 42)
    - Payroll Money Not Delivered, 1913-1937 (Volume 43)
    - Payroll Check Record for Kannapolis, 1928-1929, and Cotton and Cottonseed Meal Purchases, 1930-1936 (Volume 44)
    - Register of Employee Injuries, 1932-1936, Including Also Amazon Cotton Mills and Wiscassett Mills (Volume 45)
    - Register of Employee Injuries, 1936-1940, Including Also Amazon Cotton Mills, Tuscarora Cotton Mill, and Wiscassett Mills (Volume 46)
    - Register of Employee Injuries, 1940-1941, Including Also Amazon Cotton Mills, Tuscarora Cotton Mill, and Wiscassett Mills (Volume 47)
    - Register of Employee Injuries, 1942-1944, Including Also Amazon Cotton Mills, Wiscassett Mills, and Central Mills (Volume 48)
    - Record of Looms and Cuts, 1900, May-1916, May (Volume 49)
    - Record of Waste, Rags, Mots, Sweeps, String, Slasher, Strips, Warp, etc., Mills 1-3, 1914, July-1916, April (Volume 50)
    - Account of Goods Shipped to Cannon Mills, New York, 1909-1924, and to Cannon Manufacturing Co., San Francisco, 1910-1915 (Volume 51)
    - Freight Claims Register, 1923, Jan.-1941, Jan. (Volume 52)
    - Shipping Invoices, 1938, July-Dec. (Volume 53)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1941, with Comparison Years 1940 and 1939 (Volume 54)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1942, with Comparison Years 1941 and 1940 (Volume 55)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1943, with Comparison Years 1942 and 1941 (Volume 56)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1944, with Comparison Years 1943 and 1942 (Volume 57)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1945, with Comparison Years 1944 and 1943 (Volume 58)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1946, with Comparison Years 1945 and 1944 (Volume 59)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1947, with Comparison Years 1946 and 1945 (Volume 60)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders to Customers for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1948, with Comparison Years 1947 and 1946 (Volume 61)
    - Geographical Distribution of Billings (Shipments by Customers) for Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1953, with Comparison Years 1952 and 1951 (Volume 62)
    - Geographical Distribution of Billings (Shipments by Customers) for the Twelve Months Ended Dec., 31, 1954, with Comparison Years 1953 and 1952 (Volume 63)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders Booked for Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1954, with Comparison Years 1953 and 1952 (Volume 64)
    - Geographical Distribution of Billings Credited for Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1955, with Comparison Years 1954 and 1953 (Volume 65)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders Booked for Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1955, with Comparison Years 1954 and 1953 (Volume 66)
    - Geographical Distribution of Billings (Shipments by Customers) Credited for the Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1956, with Comparison Years 1955 and 1954 (Volume 67)
    - Geographical Distribution of Orders Booked for the Twelve Months Ended Dec. 31, 1956, with Comparison Years 1955 and 1954 (Volume 68)
    - Stock Ledger, 1896-1915 (Volume 69)
    - Stock Ledger, 1915-1920 (Volume 70)
    - Stock Ledger, 1915-1920: (Box 153)
      - Index (Box 153)
    - Stock Ledger, 1920-1928 (Volume 71)
    - Stock Ledger, 1938-1956 (Volume 72)
    - Stock Register for Shares Cancelled and for New Shares Issued, 1922 (Including: Journal Entries, pp. 50-52, for Cannon Manufacturing Co.'s, purchase of Cannon and Co., York, S.C., from J. W. Cannon and J. F. Cannon; and cotton seed sales, 1910-191?, pp. 263-268 (Volume 73)
    - Register of Stock Certificates of Mills Consolidated into Cannon Mills Company Surrendered, 1928-1930 (Volume 74)
    - Cannon Stock Issued in Exchange for Stock of Constituent Companies, 1928, Oct. 15-1929, March 2 (Volume 75)
    - Receipt Book for Stock of Mills Consolidated as Cannon Mills Company Received from Cabarrus Savings Bank, 1928-1929, 1934 (Volume 76)
    - Receipt Book for Stock Certificates of Mills Consolidated as Cannon Mills and Orders from Cabarrus Savings Bank to National City Bank for Replacement Shares in Cannon Mills, 1928-1929, 1934 (Volume 77)
    - Receipt Book for Temporary Certificates of Stock and Scrip Certificates for Fractional Shares Received from Cabarrus Savings Bank, 1928- 1929, 1934 (Volume 78)
    - Receipt Book for Temporary Certificates of Stock and Scrip Certificates Received from Cabarrus Savings Bank, 1928-1930, 1934 (Volume 79)
    - Receipt Book for Fractional Shares of Stock Received from Cabarrus Savings Bank, 1928-1929 (Volume 80)
    - Common Stock Register No. 5, Nos. 4866-5406 and 13320- 14742, 1960, Jan. 4-Dec. 30 (Volume 81)
    - Common Stock Register No. 6, Nos. 5407-5801 and 14743- 15650, 1961, Jan. 3-June 14 (Volume 82)
    - Common Stock Register No. 7, Nos. 5802-6329 and 15651- 16614, 1961, June 15-Dec. 29 (Volume 83)
    - Common Stock Register No. 8, Beginning Nos. 6330 and 16615 (Volume 84)
    - Sales Order Book, 1914-1927 (Volume 85)
    - Cotton Reports, 1916, June-1928, Sept. (Volume 86)
    - Mary Ella Hall, Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1956, July 1-1957, July 31 (Volume 87)
- Cannon Mills, Inc., Series, 1920-1974
  Primarily minutes of meetings of the stockholders and the directors of Cannon's selling agency in New York City after its incorporation in 1920. There are also scattered financial papers. Earlier files relating to the New York office are available elsewhere in the collection. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Information Folder (Box 163)
  - Financial Statements, 1920 (Box 163)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1920-1928 (Box 163)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1928-1944 (Box 163)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1945-1951 (Box 163)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1951-1957 (Box 164)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1958-1961 (Box 164)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1962-1966 (Box 164)
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1967-1974 (Box 165)
  - Private Code Book, 1934 (Box 165)
  - Sales Invoices for Klumac Cotton Mills:
    - 1934, March-Dec., 3 folders (Box 165)
- Cannon Mills Plant at York, S.C., Series, 1900-1953
  Scattered financial and production records and account books of the factory and also accounts of the company's general store that include business with millworkers. Purchased by the Cannons and operated as Cannon and Company until 1916 when the plant became a division of Cannon Manufacturing Company. The plant manufactured towels and had 14,676 spindles in 1927. It was part of Central Mills, ca. 1945-1957. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically. 166 Cannon of West Coast, Inc., Series, 1976. Minutes of the Board of Directors concerning Cannon Mills' retirement plan and trust fund. The function of this corporation remains unclear.
  - Boxed Files
    - Cannon and Company, Financial Statements, 1916 (Box 165)
    - Cannon and Company, Weekly Reports, 1916, Nov.-Dec. (Box 165)
    - Taxes:
      - Local, 1944 (Box 165)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numberical Sequence
    - York Cotton Mills Stove, Journal, 1903, Jan.-March (Volume 88)
    - York Cotton Mills Stove, Merchandise Invoices Book, 1900- 1903 (Volume 89)
    - Cannon and Company, Journal, 1913, March-1918, Sept. (Became Cannon Manufacturing Company, York Division, Nov. 1, 1916) (Volume 90)
    - Cannon and Company, Cashbook, 1913, March-1914, June, (pp. 2-33), and Central Mills, Plant No. 2 (pp. 34-398): (Volume 91)
      - Purchases Journal, 1949, May-Dec. (Box 165)
      - Drum Accounts, 1948-1951 (Box 165)
      - Bagging and Ties, 1950-1953 (Box 165)
      - Weave Sweeps Destroyed, 1950-1952 (Box 165)
      - Property Tax, 1945-1953 (Box 165)
      - List of Machinery, 1949-1952 (Items dating 1913- 1952) (Box 165)
- Cannon of West Coast, Inc., Series
  - Boxed Volume
    - Minute Book II of Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 166)
- Central Mills Series, 1930-1957
  Minutes of meetings of stockholders and directors and miscellaneous insurance and stock purchase records of this wholly owned subsidiary in Central, S.C. Cannon Mills purchased the factory in 1935 and operated it until dissolution in 1957. The factory produced print cloths and had 25,680 spindles in 1936. The plant at York, S.C., continued to function. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Insurance, 1930-1931 (Box 166)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1935-1957 (Box 166)
    - Stock Purchases, 1935, 1943 (Box 166)